Hornblower: The Even Chance is a war, adventure, tv
movie film directed by Andrew Grieve.
Portsmouth, 1794.
Under thundery skies and in lashing rain, 17-year-old midshipman Horatio Hornblower takes the first
tentative steps of his naval career, but a feud with a shipmate causes complications.
Midshipman Horatio Hornblower, played by Ioan Gruffudd.
Captain Sir Edward Pellew, played by Robert Lindsay.
Midshipman Jack Simpson, played by Dorian Healy.
Captain Keene, played by Michael Byrne.
Lieutenant Eccleston, played by Robert Bathurst.
Midshipman Clayton, played by Duncan Bell.
The Even Chance is the first of eight Hornblower television adaptations relating the exploits of
Horatio Hornblower, the protagonist in a series of novels and short stories by C.S.
The Even Chance is the name given to the film in the United Kingdom, while in
the United States it is known by the alternative title The Duel.
The film explores themes of ship, based on novel or
book, duel, napoleonic wars, 18th century.